<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>eduardoaleixo</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/</link><description>Recent content on eduardoaleixo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unnoficial Bash Strict Mode</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/bash-strict-mode/unnoficial-bash-strict-mode/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/bash-strict-mode/unnoficial-bash-strict-mode/</guid><description>Bash (and shell scripting in general) is NOT straightforward. It's easy to mess up if you don't know what you are doing. If you come from a traditional programming background and just want to plumb a few lines of code, there are a few behaviours that will confuse the hell out of you.
To help with that, the unnoficial bash strict mode was created. In this post, we will go over misleading behaviors and how the strict mode can be helpful in each case (quirks included).</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/about/</guid><description>My name is Eduardo Aleixo! I am originally from the country side Sao Paulo, now living in the capital (also named Sao Paulo). Still adapting to the big city. I currently do remote work for Translucent Computing, it's been lots of fun there!
You can contact me at eduardo@eduardoaleixo.com
I'm (at the moment) interested professionally in:
programming/operations/devops (i am a firmly believer of the devops culture) kubernetes (it's complex but we can do amazing things with it) and its ecossystem (containers, distributed systems, observability, stateless workloads) functional programming, static typing elm, haskell, elixir linux What I am currently doing at work is:</description></item></channel></rss>