<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>eduardoaleixo</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/</link><description>Recent content on eduardoaleixo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Find large files with GNU find</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/find-large-files-with-gnu-find/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/find-large-files-with-gnu-find/</guid><description>I edit my podcast using Audacity, which creates big (&amp;gt;1GB) project files (.aup3). In an ideal world, I would keep these project files, for a nice remaster when I get better at editing. In the real world, however, these files occupy space. I can technically backup them. But contrary to what people say, for the end user, storage is still expensive. I don't have the calculations in my hand right now, but it's either store in the cloud ($$$ expensive) or manage your backups at time (time expensive).</description></item><item><title>São Paulo Zoo</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/photos/2021/zoo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/photos/2021/zoo/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Run only benchmark in go(lang)</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/run-only-benchmark-go/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/run-only-benchmark-go/</guid><description>a quick go(lang) tip
let's say you have tests and benchmarks in your codebase and you want to run only benchmarks, or to put in other words, to filter out all tests from being executed
unfortunately there's no --bench-only nor anything similar available, but there's a trick popular in the community that does the job
the idea is to basically filter out all tests with an unlikely regex
1 2 3 4 go test .</description></item><item><title>search under cursor in vim</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/search-under-cursor-vim/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/search-under-cursor-vim/</guid><description>here's a vim tip i've learned recently
let's say you want to search other occurences of a keyword in that case, just press *
and then n to move forward and N (that's capital N) to move backwards
keep in mind vim's definition of keyword, ie spider-man is considered 2 words
in that (and other more advanced) cases, you may want to use visual selection
unfortunately it's not as straightforward as we would want, but here's how it is done:</description></item><item><title>ORing label selectors with kubectl</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/oring-label-selectors-with-kubectl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/oring-label-selectors-with-kubectl/</guid><description>Let's say you want, using the kubectl, to get all pods with label tier=backend OR tier=frontend.
Did you know you could do the following?
1 kubectl get pods -l &amp;#39;tier in (backend, frontend)&amp;#39; We at $WORK did not.
It's actually even more powerful, you can use notin, you can combine with , to perform AND. I recommend reading the docs for more examples.
Also, if you are at the exploration phase, don't forget to pass --show-labels to have a understanding of the existing labels.</description></item><item><title>my setup: ipad as a second monitor for quick note taking</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/ipad-second-monitor-note-taking/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/ipad-second-monitor-note-taking/</guid><description>the situation i have an old Ipad 2 (2011 model), stuck at 9.3.5 version. its screen is kinda broken, but still usable. almost no apps can be installed. it's slow. my window manager is i3. i also started using vimwiki for note taking. i set it up as a scratchpad* to be able to take notes quickly. * in i3, a scratchpad it's simply a window that does not abide to the tiling rules.</description></item><item><title>Mocking endpoints granularly in Angular</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/angular-mock-endpoint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/angular-mock-endpoint/</guid><description>Introduction At $WORK the frontend team usually develops against the real backend (exposed internally), since running the backend locally involves some additional setup (and resources, such as RAM).
The normal flows goes as follows:
Backend developers start implementing the feature Frontend devs start working on the feature only after the backend is finished Which works fine most of the time. However, sometimes a feature is being developed in parallel, so the frontend crew doesn't have an API to code against!</description></item><item><title>Unnoficial Bash Strict Mode</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/bash-strict-mode/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/bash-strict-mode/</guid><description>Bash (and shell scripting in general) is NOT straightforward. It's easy to mess up if you don't know what you are doing. If you come from a traditional programming background and just want to plumb a few lines of code, there are a few behaviours that will confuse the hell out of you.
To help with that, the unnoficial bash strict mode was created. In this post, we will go over misleading behaviors and how the strict mode can be helpful in each case (quirks included).</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/about/</guid><description>Hi, My name is Eduardo Aleixo!
You can contact me at eduardo@eduardoaleixo.com</description></item><item><title>Quem sou eu</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/quem-sou-eu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/quem-sou-eu/</guid><description>Meu nome é Eduardo Aleixo!
Voce pode me contatar em eduardo@eduardoaleixo.com</description></item></channel></rss>