<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>technical on eduardoaleixo</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/categories/technical/</link><description>Recent content in technical on eduardoaleixo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 16:09:34 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/categories/technical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Play youtube videos in the background in firefox (android)</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/youtube-videos-play-in-the-background/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 16:09:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/youtube-videos-play-in-the-background/</guid><description>Forget Youtube Vanced and NewPipe. Just use firefox + ublock. It used to work out of the box, but it apparently broke recently.
In any case, just install the &amp;ldquo;Video Background Play Fix&amp;rdquo; addon. Notice that you have to install via the builtin firefox addon list, if you open the webpage it will just download a xpi file.</description></item><item><title>Optimizing a deploy to go from ~8 minutes to ~14 seconds</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/deploy-from-8-minutes-to-14-seconds/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 18:20:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/deploy-from-8-minutes-to-14-seconds/</guid><description>As you may know, I have an alternative rock podcast called triceratops show. Its stack is pretty simple: a static website using hugo. Posts are created via Netlify CMS, which triggers a pipeline that builds the app and deploys to s3.
I noticed deploys were getting pretty slow. 5, 6, 7 minutes and sometimes even 8. It didn&amp;rsquo;t make sense, since building locally is pretty fast, and pushing to s3 should be fast, since most files won&amp;rsquo;t change.</description></item><item><title>Kill all commands that match a query</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/kill-all-commands-that-match/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 16:41:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/kill-all-commands-that-match/</guid><description>I often kill a bunch of processes with some command line incantation, like ps aux | grep $MY_QUERY | awk '{ print $2 }' | xargs kill, which as you can see, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty verbose.
I am ashamed of myself, but only recently I learned pkill has a -f flag that kills all commands (ie. the whole thing, not only the process name) that match a certain query.
We can even pair it with -i to make it case insensitive, and -l to print the PID of the affected process.</description></item><item><title>Easy release pipelines in Github with Release Please</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/easy-release-pipelines-in-github/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 11:11:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/easy-release-pipelines-in-github/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s this handy approach I use when releasing open source projects in Github that I would like to share.
The idea boils down to:
Using conventional commits to write commits in a semantic manner which can be used by tools Using Release Please to automatically create Pull Requests, which upon merge creates a Release with all the Changelog jazz. To enforce people will use conventional commits, there are couple things you need to do:</description></item><item><title>Acessing the host from a docker container</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/docker-host/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 11:04:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/docker-host/</guid><description>This is one of the things I wish I knew earlier.
When developing locally, sometimes you need a database, in those cases you can simply run docker/docker-compose, expose the port and hit that port from the development server.
When running tests, I like to use testcontainers to spin up a test db.
So host -&amp;gt; container communication is straightforward.
However, there are cases when I need to access the host from a container:</description></item><item><title>DeepCopy in Javascript</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/deep-copy-in-js/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 11:32:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/deep-copy-in-js/</guid><description>Sometimes you need to perform a deep copy in Javascript. Spread obviously doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, since it does a shallow copy. I&amp;rsquo;ve used JSON.parse(JSON.stringify), but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work with Date or other data structures, like Map and Set and others.
But recently I&amp;rsquo;ve came across the structuredClone which does what&amp;rsquo;s expected. And the support seems okay, although core-js has a polyfill.
For the full list of supported types, see the MDN docs.</description></item><item><title>`note` and `warning` in github</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/note-and-warning-in-github-markdown/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 13:02:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/note-and-warning-in-github-markdown/</guid><description>Apparently this was implemented in March 2022
1 2 3 4 5 &amp;gt; **Note** &amp;gt; This is a note &amp;gt; **Warning** &amp;gt; This is a warning Becomes</description></item><item><title>How react rendering works</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/how-react-rendering-works/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 12:22:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/how-react-rendering-works/</guid><description>Amazing blogpost going over how rendering works in react, how it&amp;rsquo;s represented internally in react, how context affects rendering, how and when to optimize using memo, how redux comes into play among other things.
I will definitely be referring to this in the future.
https://blog.isquaredsoftware.com/2020/05/blogged-answers-a-mostly-complete-guide-to-react-rendering-behavior</description></item><item><title>Good article on Message Queues</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/message-queues/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 22:50:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/message-queues/</guid><description>AMAZING article on message queues. It has a nice overview of most things one needs to know: https://sudhir.io/the-big-little-guide-to-message-queues</description></item><item><title>Scalability</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/scalability/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 15:26:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/scalability/</guid><description>We often talk how &amp;ldquo;this don&amp;rsquo;t scale&amp;rdquo;, but what does scalability mean anyway?
I&amp;rsquo;ve came across this post from all things distributed that explains it very well.
Paraphrasing from the post:
scalability means the ability to increase performance proportionally to the resources added.
Will it perform proportionally if I add more instances? Scalable. Increase its CPU? Scalable.
To give a mundane example of something that doesn&amp;rsquo;t scale, my SO and I decided to keep track of our expenses in an app.</description></item><item><title>Little's law</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/littles-law/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 15:00:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/littles-law/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve came across this interesting theorem by John Little about queues. Thing with queues is that everything is a queue! Queues in a supermarket, yes. But also requests being processed in the server, or obviously enough, a worker queue too.
The theorem is as follows:
1 L = λ * W Where L = average number of items in the queue λ = average rate of new items arriving in the queue W = average time spent in the queue</description></item><item><title>Pagination</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/pagination/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 16:28:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/pagination/</guid><description>I was looking into how to do proper pagination. I already knew about offset based pagination, normally used (among other places)in forums. It works as follows:
Each page has a fixed number of elements (eg 10), aka LIMIT in sql. When querying, you use, OFFSET to skip the first N elements. To calculate N you use current page - 1 * number of elements per page. If current page is 1, 0 * 10 is 0.</description></item><item><title>open tmux in a certain directory</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/open-tmux-in-certain-directory/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/open-tmux-in-certain-directory/</guid><description>When I start working on a project, I start tmux and then cd into its directory. There&amp;rsquo;s a simpler way to do it, though:
1 tmux new -s $SESSION_NAME -c $DIRECTORY Which then can be aliased, so I can do something like tmux-blog to start in the correct directory.
We can go ever further, and start the section with a specific layout running the commands you want:
1 2 3 4 tmux new -s blog -c $BLOG_DIR \; \ split-window &amp;#39;make serve&amp;#39; \; \ detach-client &amp;amp;&amp;amp; \ tmux attach -t blog For horizontal split use split-window -h.</description></item><item><title>Modeling UI with Discriminated Union Types</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/modeling-ui-with-discriminated-union-types/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/modeling-ui-with-discriminated-union-types/</guid><description>I like to model my app&amp;rsquo;s state using discriminated union types:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 type MyState&amp;lt;T&amp;gt; = { type: &amp;#39;pristine&amp;#39;, } | { type: &amp;#39;loading&amp;#39;, } | { type: &amp;#39;loaded&amp;#39;, data: T, } | { type: &amp;#39;failed&amp;#39;, } Reason is that it forces me to think about all states in the UI.
pristine means it&amp;rsquo;s never been touched. In most places this is the initial state which will change in a split second, normally upon first mounting the component which then starts a data load.</description></item><item><title>loki retention in k8s</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/loki-retention-in-k8s/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/loki-retention-in-k8s/</guid><description>Requirements:
running the loki-stack chart, tested with version 2.8.7 filesystem persistence enabled (ie not shipping to s3, gcs etc), which is the default in the chart To enable retention you need to have the following configs:
1 2 3 4 5 6 loki: config: compactor: retention_enabled: true limits_config: retention_period: 336h</description></item><item><title>Copy to clipboard from vim using visual selection</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/copy-to-clipboard-from-vim/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/copy-to-clipboard-from-vim/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the first time I found this tip, but the other day I was trying to find the exact syntax and couldn&amp;rsquo;t, hence this post.
Option 1 To copy to clipboard from vim using visual selection, select the thing you want (v or shift + v), then press :, it will open the command mode box (forgot what&amp;rsquo;s called) with :'&amp;lt;,'&amp;gt; prepopulated. Then just append :w !pbcopy
ie.</description></item><item><title>debugging a trigged on hover tooltip style</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/debugging-css-on-hover/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/debugging-css-on-hover/</guid><description>At $WORK we have a tooltip component triggered on hover via javascript:
Normal stuff.
But I needed to debug its styling. I know how to do that when it&amp;rsquo;s a css state, just use dev tools and set up an element state to hover.
Here, however, state is triggered via javascript, so it won&amp;rsquo;t work.
The solution, simply enough, is to go to the Debugger section, do the action (here hovering), then press F8, which is shortcut for pausing the execution.</description></item><item><title>css modules, sanitize.css and publishing a standalone react component</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/css-modules-and-css-reset/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/css-modules-and-css-reset/</guid><description>At $WORK we started with a simple web app, I think its boilerplate was copied from grafana or something, so it came with custom webpack scripts.
At some point we decided that one of its components was self contained enough and worth it to publish on its own. We moved it to lerna and published on npm. I will refer it as standalone from now on.
We noticed that the styling for the standalone component looked off.</description></item><item><title>yarn and 'Extracting tar content of undefined failed, the file appears to be corrupt'</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/yarn-corrupted/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/yarn-corrupted/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a funny one.
One day, at $WORK, CI started to fail when running yarn install:
1 2 3 4 error https://registry.yarnpkg.com/ol/-/ol-6.12.0.tgz: Extracting tar content of undefined failed, the file appears to be corrupt: &amp;#34;ENOENT: no such file or directory, chmod &amp;#39;/home/runner/.cache/yarn/v6/npm-ol-6.12.0-0de51abad0aaeb0eca41cba3c6d26ee485a3e92b-integrity/node_modules/ol/format/KML.js&amp;#39;&amp;#34; After some digging we found that&amp;rsquo;s due to a race condition that made yarn pull the same dependency in parallel.
The workaround? yarn --network-concurrency=1
And that was fine for a while.</description></item><item><title>from i3 to yabai / setting up a new mac</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/from-i3-to-yabai/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/from-i3-to-yabai/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using linux (fedora/arch) + i3 for a few years by now.
Then I got a mac for work.
To be fair, I &amp;gt;asked&amp;lt; for a mac because I wanted to experiment the whole arm hype. Spoiler: it&amp;rsquo;s quite good indeed. Worth it disrupting an existing flow? Don&amp;rsquo;t know yet.
But anyway, I had a whole setup in linux that I had to adapt to this new machine. Some of it it&amp;rsquo;s just second-system syndrome (like keeping track of installed tools), some of it are indeed things I had to adapt.</description></item><item><title>'Too many authentication failures' when using SSH with password</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/ssh-too-many-authentication-failures-with-password/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/ssh-too-many-authentication-failures-with-password/</guid><description>Disclaimer: This happened some time ago and the details are fuzzy. This post only purposes is for my own documentation.
I have a raspberry pi running here and didn&amp;rsquo;t bother to set up pubkey authentication.
After adding new SSH keys to my personal machine, SSHing to the raspberry pi failed with
1 Too many authentication failures Which did not make sense at all.
I remember looking at the SSH Server logs and realizing it was still trying to login using my SSH keys, but since none of them were set up in this server, it was hitting the MaxAuthTries limit (I think by default it&amp;rsquo;s 6).</description></item><item><title>Creating Windows bootable USB on Linux</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/creating-windows-bootable-usb-on-linux/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/creating-windows-bootable-usb-on-linux/</guid><description>This is more for self documentation than anything else.
Had positive results using WoeUSB (https://github.com/woeusb/WoeUSB)
1 fdisk -l Then
1 sudo ./woeusb-5.2.4.bash --device $ISO_FILENAME $DEVICE Eg.
1 sudo ./woeusb-5.2.4.bash --device Win10_21H2_English_x64.iso /dev/sdd</description></item><item><title>Export Firefox Synced Tabs</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/export-firefox-synced-tabs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/export-firefox-synced-tabs/</guid><description>I tend to have many tabs open. Like way too many. I first noticed this behaviour when the tabs counter in my browser became a smile.
But that is fine, everybody knows someone like that, hell, you may even be that person.
What I am here to talk about is a healthy routine I&amp;rsquo;ve developed: from time to time (ideally once a month), close all tabs. But hey, firefox has a feature that allos closing old tabs automatically, somebody may say.</description></item><item><title>ALB Controller with AWS Cognito and Google Oauth</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/aws-cognito-alb-controller/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/aws-cognito-alb-controller/</guid><description>At $WORK we needed to expose some apps that don&amp;rsquo;t have a login flow (eg alertmanager, prometheus), these are running in kubernetes.
Since I found the documentation a little bit confusing I decided to create this blogpost to document to others (here myself from the future included).
Most examples here will be in terraform, which can be easily translated to the UI.
Requirements ExternalDNS setup A domain you already know All required permissions to create all necessary stuff First let&amp;rsquo;s create a user pool and a domain.</description></item><item><title>picture-in-picture in i3</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/picture-in-picture-i3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/picture-in-picture-i3/</guid><description>intro Sometimes I want to make an arbitrary window to be &amp;ldquo;picture-in-picture&amp;rdquo;, ie for that window to be above all others, without affecting their layout.
And most importantly, I also want that behaviour to be consistent across workspaces.
A prime example of that is zoom calls, where I may jump between workspaces while we are talking about different subjects.
meat Luckily i3 supports that well quite easily by using sticky floating windows.</description></item><item><title>Vimwiki/Taskwiki diary template</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/vimwiki-diary-template/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/vimwiki-diary-template/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using a vim + vimwiki + taskwiki + taskwarrior + timewarrior setup for a while. It works really well!
(One day I will try org-mode. Not today though)
One of the bits that got a good impression is the diary template. Basically it contains:
A header The list of tasks that haven&amp;rsquo;t been completed The list of tasks completed on that day 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 #!</description></item><item><title>Setting up evdi after updating kernel to 5.15.12</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/setting-up-evdi-after-updating-kernel-to-5-15-12/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/setting-up-evdi-after-updating-kernel-to-5-15-12/</guid><description>intro as you may know, I use an old ipad as a second screen. in a nutshell, it relies on the evdi kernel module to create a virtual display which is then accessed by the ipad via a VNC Viewer.
pne quirk is that almost every time I update the kernel, evdi (and consequently my ipad setup) also breaks. I am not super familiar with kernel shenanigans so I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s a fundamental issue or not.</description></item><item><title>Continuously check code coverage while developing tests in go</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/go-tests-and-coverage-continuously/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/go-tests-and-coverage-continuously/</guid><description>I have this workflow where while developing tests I also check for code coverage. The idea is to see if I am really touching that piece of code I am adding tests for. Similar to TDD, there&amp;rsquo;s a certain primal endorphine rush from seeing the coverage go from red to green.
In a nutshell, it works like this:
1 go test ./... -coverprofile=coverage.out &amp;amp;&amp;amp; go tool cover -html=coverage.out The first bit will create a coverage.</description></item><item><title>Find large files with GNU find</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/find-large-files-with-gnu-find/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/find-large-files-with-gnu-find/</guid><description>I edit my podcast using Audacity, which creates big (&amp;gt;1GB) project files (.aup3). In an ideal world, I would keep these project files, for a nice remaster when I get better at editing. In the real world, however, these files occupy space. I can technically backup them. But contrary to what people say, for the end user, storage is still expensive. I don&amp;rsquo;t have the calculations in my hand right now, but it&amp;rsquo;s either store in the cloud ($$$ expensive) or manage your backups at time (time expensive).</description></item><item><title>Run only benchmark in go(lang)</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/run-only-benchmark-go/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/run-only-benchmark-go/</guid><description>a quick go(lang) tip
let&amp;rsquo;s say you have tests and benchmarks in your codebase and you want to run only benchmarks, or to put in other words, to filter out all tests from being executed
unfortunately there&amp;rsquo;s no --bench-only nor anything similar available, but there&amp;rsquo;s a trick popular in the community that does the job
the idea is to basically filter out all tests with an unlikely regex
1 2 3 4 go test .</description></item><item><title>search under cursor in vim</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/search-under-cursor-vim/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/search-under-cursor-vim/</guid><description>here&amp;rsquo;s a vim tip i&amp;rsquo;ve learned recently
let&amp;rsquo;s say you want to search other occurences of a keyword in that case, just press *
and then n to move forward and N (that&amp;rsquo;s capital N) to move backwards
keep in mind vim&amp;rsquo;s definition of keyword, ie spider-man is considered 2 words
in that (and other more advanced) cases, you may want to use visual selection
unfortunately it&amp;rsquo;s not as straightforward as we would want, but here&amp;rsquo;s how it is done:</description></item><item><title>ORing label selectors with kubectl</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/oring-label-selectors-with-kubectl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/oring-label-selectors-with-kubectl/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s say you want, using the kubectl, to get all pods with label tier=backend OR tier=frontend.
Did you know you could do the following?
1 kubectl get pods -l &amp;#39;tier in (backend, frontend)&amp;#39; We at $WORK did not.
It&amp;rsquo;s actually even more powerful, you can use notin, you can combine with , to perform AND. I recommend reading the docs for more examples.
Also, if you are at the exploration phase, don&amp;rsquo;t forget to pass --show-labels to have a understanding of the existing labels.</description></item><item><title>my setup: ipad as a second monitor for quick note taking</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/ipad-second-monitor-note-taking/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/ipad-second-monitor-note-taking/</guid><description>the situation i have an old Ipad 2 (2011 model), stuck at 9.3.5 version. its screen is kinda broken, but still usable. almost no apps can be installed. it&amp;rsquo;s slow. my window manager is i3. i also started using vimwiki for note taking. i set it up as a scratchpad* to be able to take notes quickly. * in i3, a scratchpad it&amp;rsquo;s simply a window that does not abide to the tiling rules.</description></item><item><title>Mocking endpoints granularly in Angular</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/angular-mock-endpoint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/angular-mock-endpoint/</guid><description>Introduction At $WORK the frontend team usually develops against the real backend (exposed internally), since running the backend locally involves some additional setup (and resources, such as RAM).
The normal flows goes as follows:
Backend developers start implementing the feature Frontend devs start working on the feature only after the backend is finished Which works fine most of the time. However, sometimes a feature is being developed in parallel, so the frontend crew doesn&amp;rsquo;t have an API to code against!</description></item><item><title>Unnoficial Bash Strict Mode</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/bash-strict-mode/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/bash-strict-mode/</guid><description>Bash (and shell scripting in general) is NOT straightforward. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to mess up if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what you are doing. If you come from a traditional programming background and just want to plumb a few lines of code, there are a few behaviours that will confuse the hell out of you.
To help with that, the unnoficial bash strict mode was created. In this post, we will go over misleading behaviors and how the strict mode can be helpful in each case (quirks included).</description></item></channel></rss>