<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>life on eduardoaleixo</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/categories/life/</link><description>Recent content in life on eduardoaleixo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 11:25:14 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Low + Dirty Three: Gospel do Bem</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/low-dirty-three-gospel-do-bem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 11:25:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/low-dirty-three-gospel-do-bem/</guid><description>Lais recomendou o projeto &amp;ldquo;In the Fishtank&amp;rdquo; que junta dois ou mais artistas pra fazer um álbum em um final de semana.
Inicialmente estava estudando o Sonic Youth + The Ex.
Agora ouvi o Low + Dirty Three. Pra variar última faixa do álbum é o que me conquistou. Um gospel do bem, tal qual Spiritualized.</description></item><item><title>Primavera Sound Porto 2023: Part 1</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/primavera-sound-2023-pt-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 19:40:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/primavera-sound-2023-pt-1/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to go to a &amp;gt;real&amp;lt; (alternative) rock festival. Back in the day Brazil there were a few, like Tim Festival (previously Free Jazz), Planeta Terra etc. However I was too young and too poor to attend to any of them. When I loved in Toronto there was Osheaga, which my wife attended but I didn&amp;rsquo;t (we weren&amp;rsquo;t dating at the time). So when moving to Portugal we definitely wanted to attend a festival, specifically Primavera Sound, which is now a classic one.</description></item><item><title>Shellac Concert</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/shellac-concert/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 19:13:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/shellac-concert/</guid><description>Shellac is one of my favorites bands. It&amp;rsquo;s punk, noisy, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take itself too seriously etc. Every song I feel like &amp;ldquo;this is the kind of song I would want to do if I had a band again&amp;rdquo;.
The location was in a place called B.Leza, which a pun with Beleza, aka &amp;ldquo;cool&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s near the pier, so a nice atmosphere!
The opening act was by the portuguese artist Puçanga, not really my cup of tea and I don&amp;rsquo;t think it had anything to do with Shellac, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t spoil the fun.</description></item><item><title>Swans Concert</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/swans-concert/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 18:44:52 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/swans-concert/</guid><description>We went to a Swans concert at Culturgest(28 euros each ticket). It&amp;rsquo;s walking distance from home, which is pretty convenient!
We got right on time for the opening, so most seats were occupied. They were reserved ones and we had trouble finding ours. For some reason here the numbers are on the back of the seats, so it&amp;rsquo;s kinda difficult to find yours. We got the second row, which in retrospect may be too close.</description></item><item><title>kkk, cá-cá, quiá quiá and きゃっきゃっ and some other coincidences in language</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/kya-kya/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 17:21:05 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/kya-kya/</guid><description>In my Japanese studies I&amp;rsquo;ve stumbled upon the きゃっきゃっ (kya-kya) onomatopoeia, which represents playful, laughter of children.
In Brazilian Portuguese we usually laugh with KKK (which sometimes evokes fear in the Anglo word due the pointy hat association). It&amp;rsquo;s a corruption of &amp;ldquo;quá quá quá&amp;rdquo; used in comics, it came into shape in the 90s and 2000s with the Internet and its tendency to abbreviate things. Mostly (I believe) an influence from the English language and its many acronyms.</description></item><item><title>Maracas de Fogo by Lula Côrtes and Zé Ramalho</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/maracas-de-fogo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 12:22:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/maracas-de-fogo/</guid><description>A long time ago I was at a party (or a club, or a discotecagem before a show) and this incredible song started playing. I remember the floor was pretty empty, which baffled me since the playlist seemed pretty good.
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t identify what it was, I asked my friends that raised their shoulders. I took the courage and asked the DJ. I immediately took notes, and saved the video on YouTube.</description></item><item><title>Review: Guardians of the Galaxy</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/review-guardians-of-the-galaxy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 23:44:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/review-guardians-of-the-galaxy/</guid><description>In preparation for the Guardians of the Galaxy 3, my SO and I watched the previous two movies (first time for her), then we went to the movies watch the third one.
It&amp;rsquo;s interesting that the I watched the 3 movies at completely different points of my life. It felt nostalgic.
The first movie is pretty solid, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing to say that you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard it before.
The second one I didn&amp;rsquo;t like it when I first watched.</description></item><item><title>Review: Summer Time Rendering (Anime)</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/review-summer-time-rendering/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 23:34:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/review-summer-time-rendering/</guid><description>Summer Time Rendering is a 2022 anime based on a manga of the same name. It was totally outside my radar, until Hideo Kojima recommended on twitter.
It starts really strong. There&amp;rsquo;s some some slice of life, mystery and even some terror. The plot is smart enough, although for the otakus some of its plot points may be not so original.
I liked that it passes in Tomogashima, Wakayama, although it has a different name.</description></item><item><title>Play youtube videos in the background in firefox (android)</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/youtube-videos-play-in-the-background/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 16:09:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/youtube-videos-play-in-the-background/</guid><description>Forget Youtube Vanced and NewPipe. Just use firefox + ublock. It used to work out of the box, but it apparently broke recently.
In any case, just install the &amp;ldquo;Video Background Play Fix&amp;rdquo; addon. Notice that you have to install via the builtin firefox addon list, if you open the webpage it will just download a xpi file.</description></item><item><title>Review: Shame Concert</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/review-shame-concert/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 18:53:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/review-shame-concert/</guid><description>On Saturady, 18 March 2023, my wife and I attended a shame concert (a somewhat hyped english &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;post punk&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&amp;quot;&amp;quot; band). These are my impressions.
To be fair, we almost didn&amp;rsquo;t go. Earlier in the day we went eat pastéis (salty, the brazilian flavor ones), then later we got a pizza. お腹が痛い。
The doors opened a 8pm. The opening band was scheduled to start at 9pm. We were there at 8h50pm.</description></item><item><title>Review: Videodrome (1983)</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/review-videodrome/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 20:17:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/review-videodrome/</guid><description>Watched in a movie theater, thanks to CinePop. 4 Euros each ticket, cheap enough to watch a Cronenberg classic.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t thought enough about this, so I will just dump a bunch of unconnected thoughts. Nothing very different from my usual posts.
Replace TV for Internet and it still works Late night TV soft porn Snuff films Gore, who watches that and why? James Woods is manipulated by the Media Pirate radio/TV Still happened in the 90s Baudrillard&amp;rsquo;s Simulacra &amp;amp; Simulation Serial Experiments Lain eXistenZ VTubers and Internet nicknames &amp;ldquo;Soon, all of us will have special names&amp;rdquo; Total Recall vibes Specially the special effects, obviously enough Conservatives using the exact same methods they criticize Marshall McLuhan&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The media is the message&amp;rdquo; Watching in the theaters is definitely different from watching from home Debbie Harry She is pretty in this film, but she reminds me someone else The Ring/Ringu &amp;ldquo;Forbidden tape&amp;rdquo; Does media make us violent?</description></item><item><title>Review: Africa Addio (1966)</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/review-africa-addio/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 12:08:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/review-africa-addio/</guid><description>I have an extensive list of movies to watch that sparked my interest somehow. I don&amp;rsquo;t keep notes on why I wanted to watch them, or where I first learned about them. Most often, enough time passes that when I finally get to watch it, I have no idea what&amp;rsquo;s it about. It ends up being a good strategy, since I get to see it with completely fresh eyes.
This week I got to watch Africa Addio (1996), or Africa: Blood and Guts.</description></item><item><title>TIL: Ken Shimura invented the 'Saisho wa gu' from Janken</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/saisho-wa-gu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 15:58:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/saisho-wa-gu/</guid><description>TIL, the japanese comedian Ken Shimura was the first to invent/popularize the phrase you say/sing before playing janken (aka rock paper scissors, or jokempo in portuguese) in japanese.
Source: https://twitter.com/JapanRPS/status/1244448876225912832</description></item><item><title>Review: The Bear Season 1</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/the-bear/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 16:39:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/the-bear/</guid><description>I finally watched The Bear. Friends recommended it to me back in July 2022, but as always, I prefer to wait and see if it stands the test of time.
And it does. I mean, by the time I am writing this only half an year has passed, but enough recommendations from different people came in, so I could be sure it had enough impact on people.
The show itself is about a chef taking over his brother&amp;rsquo;s restaurant in Chicago.</description></item><item><title>Everything has a meta</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/everything-has-a-meta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 20:38:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/everything-has-a-meta/</guid><description>Any gamer knows about the &amp;ldquo;meta&amp;rdquo;, supposedly an acronym for &amp;ldquo;most effective tactics available&amp;rdquo;, which just means the current best strategy to win the game. In Rocket League, the game I am mostly familiar with, the meta has changed from hitting the backboard, to bumping/demoing the opponent, ballchasing, flip resets etc.
Lately the term has taken a broad approach, referring to other things other than gaming, very similarly to the Brazilian Portuguese word &amp;ldquo;manha&amp;rdquo;, meaning ability to perform something, or quirk.</description></item><item><title>Review: O Natal do Bruno Aleixo</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/o-natal-do-bruno-aleixo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 17:40:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/o-natal-do-bruno-aleixo/</guid><description>Back in ~2008 Bruno Aleixo became famous in the underground Brazilian internet culture with its weird sketches that were streets ahead of what we knew.
Bruno Aleixo and Busto (which is literally a bust statue of Napoleon) playing Street Fighter 2 is still to this day one of the funniest things I&amp;rsquo;ve seen, and still lives in a lots of people&amp;rsquo;s collective memory. For a quick reference, when I told a friend I was going to see his movie, he promptly asked: &amp;ldquo;is that the guy from the Street Fighter sketch?</description></item><item><title>Review: Brought to Light: Thirty Years of Drug Smuggling, Arms Deals, and Covert Action</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/brought-tolight/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 14:21:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/brought-tolight/</guid><description>The other day I read Brought to Light: Thirty Years of Drug Smuggling, Arms Deals, and Covert Action, by Alan Moore and Bill Sienkiewicz. It&amp;rsquo;s available for free in the Internet Archive.
It&amp;rsquo;s a short (64 pages) comic book on basically some of the dirty work by the CIA in the XX century. I can see 2 big groups of people reading it: those that already know most of the story, and those who don&amp;rsquo;t.</description></item><item><title>んです</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/%E3%82%93%E3%81%A7%E3%81%99/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 19:27:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/%E3%82%93%E3%81%A7%E3%81%99/</guid><description>In Japanese, the んです grammar is used often and with so many subtleties it&amp;rsquo;s a classic problem we beginners face.
Thankfully I&amp;rsquo;ve found a series of blog posts that in such a thorough way!
italki - Language As A Window Into Culture: Mastering The Nuances Of んです - Part 1 italki - Language As A Window Into Culture: Mastering The Nuances Of んです - Part 2 italki - Language As A Window Into Culture: Mastering The Nuances Of んです - Part 3 I will surely revisit these topics sometime in the near future.</description></item><item><title>Douglas Adams on our reaction to Technological Progress</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/douglas-adams-on-reaction-to-technological-progress/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 15:22:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2023/douglas-adams-on-reaction-to-technological-progress/</guid><description>Interesting quote from Douglas Adams:
“I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with a set of rules that describe our reactions to technologies:
Anything that is in the world when you’re born is normal and ordinary and is just a natural part of the way the world works. Anything that&amp;rsquo;s invented between when you’re fifteen and thirty-five is new and exciting and revolutionary and you can probably get a career in it. Anything invented after you&amp;rsquo;re thirty-five is against the natural order of things.</description></item><item><title>playing pokemon violet in japanese cheatsheet</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/playing-pokemon-violet-in-japanese/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/playing-pokemon-violet-in-japanese/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing Pokemon Violet in japanese. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely challenging to both my japanese skills and my patience. I frequently skip text messages, making me miss some important info. On the other hand, it makes me feel like a child again, learning new things one at a time.
But anyway, here are a few useful links:
Type chart As a 90s child, I&amp;rsquo;ve played pokemon. I remember most of the counters, but some of them I do not (eg.</description></item><item><title>The Fugitive (1993)</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/the-fugitive/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/the-fugitive/</guid><description>The other day we caught the movie US Marshals on TV. I always thought it was a crappy movie due to its subtitle in Brazil: &amp;ldquo;Os Federais&amp;rdquo;, ie &amp;ldquo;The Federals&amp;rdquo;. It was surprisingly a good movie! I mean, it went into the category &amp;ldquo;I liked it, but wouldn&amp;rsquo;t watch again&amp;rdquo; which to me is a win. Also it was a perfect movie for a lazy Saturday.
I liked Wesley Snipes there, there was an young Robert Downey Jr.</description></item><item><title>How I record my podcasts</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/how-i-record-my-podcasts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/how-i-record-my-podcasts/</guid><description>As you may be aware, I have a music podcast called Triceratops Show.
Since I had to setup my recording environment again in a mac, I decided to document it here.
For recording I basically use OBS.
The trick is to record both my microphone and the computer audio as 2 separate tracks, so that we can sync them later.
Turns out that&amp;rsquo;s not as easy as I would hope.</description></item><item><title>downloading subtitles from youtube to help studying japanese</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/downloading-subtitles-from-youtube/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/2022/downloading-subtitles-from-youtube/</guid><description>intro As you may know, I&amp;rsquo;ve been studying Japanese for a while. It&amp;rsquo;s a super difficult language for us European language speakers. There&amp;rsquo;s the alphabets (3!) to learn, the grammar, vocabulary etc.
Right now I am at a point where I don&amp;rsquo;t have to look up every single vocabulary and have some basic grasp of grammar. I haven&amp;rsquo;t taken the official test but I am pretty sure I can pass the JLPT N5 test.</description></item><item><title>Adding more addresses than allowed in MercadoLivre</title><link>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/adding-more-address-than-allowed-in-mercadolive/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eduardoaleixo.com/posts/adding-more-address-than-allowed-in-mercadolive/</guid><description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been more empathic, affable, gentle etc. I don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly why. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s because I am getting older. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s something else.
So for this year (2021) I decided to buy something to give to people I know. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be anything fancy so I decided to get them a chocotone, which is basically a panettone (Christmas bread) but with chocolate.
Since I am, first of all, a male, and second of all, lazy.</description></item></channel></rss>